rocketium.com 2019-05-18

# Our Privacy Policy | Rocketium

### Information we may collect from you:

We may collect and process the following information about you:

### Information you provide to us

You give us your email address before you get started with your first video at Rocketium.com. Depending on how you use the Services, you may be required to provide certain personally identifiable information ( **"personal information"** ). Which may include, but is not limited to the following: 

Name 

Email address 

Contact number 

Industry you belong to 

Company 

Title / Designation / Role 

Username for social media accounts such as Facebook, Twitter, and Google 

Financial and credit card information 

Profile picture, your image, or any other image / video clip if you include it in any media content that you upload or include in the videos that you create using our Services (hereinafter collectively referred to as **"User Content"** ). 

By providing us with this information, you expressly consent to our use of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Any data that is necessary to process your subscription request is mandatory, the consequence of the refusal to provide it, is that we will not process said subscription request, on the other hand any information that is not necessary to process your subscription request is not mandatory and the refusal to provide it has no consequence on the processing of your said subscription request. 

### Information we may collect about you

We collect navigational information about what Rocketium.com pages you access or visit, your device's Internet Protocol "IP" address, information about your mobile device (such as operating system of your mobile device or browser type), the URLs of websites that referred you to us, non-precise geographic location, screen recordings, technical information about your device, system and App software and peripherals, date and time stamps and other metadata concerning your User Content associated with your usage of our Services, system configuration information and messages, phone numbers and e-mail addresses when you choose to reach out to us via these communication channels including but not limited to phone, email and chatbot services. 

ROCKETIUM.COM APP ACTIVATION AND AUTOMATIC UPDATES: When you activate your Rocketium.com App or when you install updates to the App, we collect certain information about your device. Some of our Apps include features that connect to our servers and offer you the ability to install updates to the App. We may keep track of information such as whether the update was successful or not. We may use the information collected through activation or App updates to validate your copy of the App and confirm that it is genuine and properly licensed. 

### Information we receive from other sources

Rocketium.com App and Site may include buttons, tools, or content that link to other third-party services (for example, a Facebook "Like" button). We may collect information about your use of these features. In addition, when you see or interact with these buttons, tools, or content, or view a Rocketium.com web page or App containing them, some information from your browser may automatically be sent to the other company. 

### Storage and transfer of personal information

Your personal information and files are stored on Rocketium.com's servers and the servers of companies we hire to provide services to us. Your personal information may be transferred across national borders because we have servers located in US and EU, and the companies we hire to help us run our business may be located in different countries around the world. 

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored in, a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. The laws in some countries may not provide as much legal protection for your information as in the EEA. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access. 

### GDPR

Please review our dedicated [page](https://rocketium.com/gdpr-compliance.html) to learn more about our approach to GDPR. 

### Cookies

Cookies are bits of electronic information that a website may transfer to a visitor's computer to identify specific information about the visitor's visits to a website. The Site uses a browser feature known as a cookie, which assigns a unique identification to your computer. We also use localstorage for session and persistent information. In case you do not wish us to collect such information kindly refer to our cookie policy to opt out. You can access the details of our Cookie Policy [here](https://rocketium.com/cookie-policy.html). If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that store cookies. Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide variety of browsers. However, please note that if you disable the use of cookies on your computer, some functionalities of our Services will not work. 

### Use of information

We may use your personal information not limited to the following purposes: 

  * To administer your use of our Services
  * To better understand your needs and interests
  * To better understand and improvise our products and services
  * To facilitate your use and personalizing your experience on the Site
  * To respond to your inquiries or fulfilling your requests for information about our Services
  * To provide you with information about our Services and sending you information and materials from Rocketium.com including marketing communication
  * To help you address problems with the Site, including any technical problems
  * To Process online job application, you have applied for
  * To detect and prevent identity theft, fraud, and other potentially illegal acts as well as protecting the integrity of the website
  * To respond to subpoenas, court orders, or judicial processes
  * To provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety
  * To resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems
  * To help with any investigations or complaints
  * To provide you with relevant information or Services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you based on previous interactions, where you have consented to be contacted

We use the information we collect in a variety of ways. Generally, using all of the above mentioned, and similar type tools, we may collect, aggregate, and use information from or about you such as data about the type of browser and operating system used, which web pages you view, the time and duration or you visits to our Site, the search queries you may use on the Site, whether you clicked on any advertisements, whether you have clicked on any links in any e-mails sent from us, or third-parties on our behalf, whether you have chosen to opt-out of certain services or information sharing, and whether you have viewed or ordered certain products or services. 

### Information sharing and disclosure:

Rocketium.com provides your personal information to third parties who in turn help us run our business. These third parties include but are not limited to business partners, suppliers, sub-contractors, advertisers & advertising networks, analytics & search engine providers, payment providers. We may also share with or sell to third parties aggregate information or information that does not personally identify you. _Should you require more details on third parties we work with or have any questions around it, you may write to us at contact@rocketium.com._

We use payment gateways such as Stripe, Inc to manage our payments, but we reserve the right to change this service provider at any time for any reason. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards. Your credit card information will also be subject to our payment processor's privacy policy in addition to ours. PLEASE READ THE PRIVACY POLICY ON THE WEBSITE OF ANY PAYMENT PROCESSOR THAT YOU ARE DIRECTED TO REGARDING THE USE, STORAGE AND PROTECTION OF YOUR CREDIT CARD INFORMATION BEFORE SUBMITTING ANY CREDIT CARD INFORMATION. Rocketium.com complies with all legal requirements of your State's applicable laws regarding providing refunds for unauthorized charges. When you make a charge, we shall display a completed charge screen. This is your electronic receipt. You should print or save this electronic receipt for your records. YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU HAVE THE LEGAL RIGHT TO USE ANY CREDIT CARDS, DEBIT CARDS OR OTHER PAYMENT MEANS USED TO INITIATE ANY TRANSACTION. 

We may also share your personal information in the following circumstances 

  * When we are required to provide information in response to a subpoena, court order, or other applicable law or legal process.
  * When we have a good faith belief that the disclosure is necessary to prevent or respond to fraud, defend our apps or websites against attacks, or protect the property and safety of Rocketium.com, our customers and users, or the public.
  * If we merge with or are acquired by another company, sell a Rocketium.com website, app, or business unit, or if all or a substantial portion of our assets are acquired by another company. In those cases, your information will likely be one of the assets that is transferred.

There are several places within the Site and our Apps that allow you to post comments, upload pictures, or submit content for others to see. Rocketium.com will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on our Services according to the preferences you set in your account. Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want others to know about you. Please consider carefully what information you disclose in your profile page and your desired level of anonymity. You can review and revise your profile information at any time. To remove the content, you have shared on the Site or our Apps, you may use the same features (available on the Site/Apps) to do so. In case you have any query regarding removal and or deletion of such contact you can write to us at [contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com)

Our blog is managed by a third-party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We will post any personal information here only after we take your permission. You can write to us at [contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com) if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third-party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy. 

We display personal testimonials of customers on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com)

### Linked sites

Some of the functionality on our Services may be provided by third parties that are not affiliated with Rocketium.com. These entities may collect or receive certain information about your use of our Services and your activities over time and across different websites, including through the use of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, third-party cookies, web beacons, or other tracking technologies. Rocketium.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of these entities. In addition, our Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us. Such websites are not under our control and we are not responsible for their privacy policies or practices. If you provide any personal information through any such third-party website, we recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices of that third party. 

### Social networking

You may choose to enable or log in to our Services via various online services, including social networking services like Facebook. Our services also may enable you to access social networking services such as Facebook, Twitter, or Google (collectively, "Social Network") directly or indirectly through our Services. 

When you link a Social Network account to our Apps or log into our Services using your Social Network account, we may collect relevant information necessary to enable our Services to access that Social Network and your data contained within that Social Network. We may share your information with the operator of that Social Network to facilitate or enhance delivery of that Social Network or other services to you. A Social Network may provide us with access to certain information that you have provided to them, and we will use, store, and disclose such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Additionally, a Social Network may collect personal information and information about your use of our Site or Services automatically. The manner in which a Social Network collects, uses, stores, and discloses your information is governed by the policies of such third parties and Rocketium.com shall have no liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of any Social Network that may be enabled within its Services. 

### Your rights

_Right to be informed:_ You are entitled to know whether we hold your personal information and the purpose your personal data is processed for. 

_Right of access:_ You are entitled to know the categories of your personal data being processed, the purposes of such processing, and the details of third parties to whom the data may have been disclosed. **Please reach out to contact@rocketium.com for more information on third party vendors.**

_Right to rectification:_ You are entitled to correct / update your personal information available with us. 

_Right to erasure:_ You are entitled to get your data erased from our databases. Please note that we might need to retain certain information about you for reasons including but not limited to legal, internal business and fraud prevention. We will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide you with the services you are eligible to use and as needed to comply with our legal obligations and enforce our agreements. 

_Right to data portability:_ You are entitled to obtain and reuse your personal data. You can either obtain the data from us or, in turn, provide it to a third party (if you so wish), or ask us to transfer your personal data directly to a third party. 

_Right to object / restrict processing or both:_ You have a right to object / restrict the processing of your data in some circumstances, including where the data is inaccurate (for the period during which we are verifying the data), the data is no longer required in light of the purpose of processing, or in connection with direct marketing (you can prevent / discontinue marketing communications to you by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your personal data), or by utilizing opt-out mechanisms in the emails we send you 

In the above cases, we will retain minimum personal data to note that you opted out from being contacted again. 

_For raising requests pertaining to the above-mentioned rights, please write to us at[contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com). Please note some of the rights mentioned herein may not be available as we are designing the technical capabilities to comply with such requests; having said the above Rocketium.com will do its best to resolve your request to the best of its ability._

### Security

We understand that the security of your personal information is important. We provide reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security controls to protect your personal information. However, despite our efforts, no security controls are 100% effective and Rocketium.com cannot ensure or warrant the security of your personal information. 

### Privacy of children

We recognize the importance of children's safety and privacy. We do not request, or knowingly collect, any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. Rocketium.com is very sensitive to privacy issues regarding children. _By visiting this Site or providing your personal information to one of our call-centre operators or live chat representatives or starting your free trial or signing up or logging in you are claiming yourself to be 16 years of age or above._

WARNING: Any personal information (e.g., name, email address, personal photographs) that you voluntarily disclose in any video may be collected and used by parties other than us and may result in unsolicited messages from other parties. If you believe that any child under the age of 16 has posted any personal information anywhere on our website, please contact us immediately at [contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com) and provide as much information as you can to help us locate and delete the personal information. If you post personal information in any video, we have no control over this use of your personal information and, as such, cannot be responsible for it. 

If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child or any other child under the age of 16 has provided us with personal information, he or she should write to us at [contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com). 

### California's Do Not Track Notice

Rocketium.com does not have a mechanism in place for responding to browser "do not track" signals or other similar mechanisms used to limit collection of information for use in Online Behavioral Advertising. There currently is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Therefore, like many websites and online services, the Services do not alter their practices when they receive a "Do Not Track" signal from a visitor's browser. To find out more about "Do Not Track," please visit http://www.allaboutdnt.com. 

### Changes to our privacy policy

Our Services may change from time to time. As a result, we reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. If we make any material changes to the way we use or disclose your personal information, we will notify you by email, at the email address you have provided to us. If you object to any changes you must cease using our Services. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically by visiting this webpage. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated at the top of this page. Your continued use of our Services after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy or receipt of the email indicated herein, indicates your agreement to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy. 

### Questions / changes in policy

Rocketium.com welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you believe that we have not adhered to this Policy or If you have questions or concerns with respect to our Privacy Policy, please write to us at [contact@rocketium.com](mailto:contact@rocketium.com) .
